A Finding Aid to the Pietro Lazzari Papers, 1878-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lazzpiet
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1878-1980, undated; Series 8; (boxes 8-12, 13, MGP 1, MGP 4; 3.8 linear ft.)
  Photographs of miscellaneous celebrities include: Johnny Weissmuller with Leslie Howard, undated; Silvana Mangano (autographed photo of actress), undated; Angelo Musco (actor?), undated; Piacentini (autographed photo of boxer), 1921; Cesare Impenado (autographed photo of athlete), 1925; and Mauricio d'Oncoro (?) (autographed photo of actor), 1962. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Lazzari, [1914]-1977; (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Lazzari and his family, [circa 1955-1960] (Box 8)
  - Family and friends, 1878-1969; (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Family and friends, cont., 1878-1969; (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous celebrities, 1921-1962 (Box 9)
  - Lazzari's studio, 1952-1977; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Lazzari at work in his studio, 1947-1980 (Box 9)
  - Lazzari working on statue of Dr. Edward Minor Gallaudet, 1968-1970; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Lazzari's art classes, undated (Box 9)
  - Artist's models, undated; (4 folders; 3 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1) (Box 9)
  - Reference photographs for artwork, 1944-1966 (Box 9)
    - Statue of Dr. Edward Minor Gallaudet, undated (Box 9)
    - Bust of Eleanor Roosevelt, 1944-1962; (5 folders) (Box 9)
    - Bust of Adlai Stevenson, 1952-1963; (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - John Rust, [1952-1954] (Box 9)
    - President Lyndon Johnson and family at social events (see also sol 13), 1962-1966 (Box 9)
    - Pope Paul VI, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Portraits of miscellaneous individuals (including Oscar L. Chapman, Senator John McClellan, and Sir John Boyd Orr), 1962-1965 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous individuals (see also sol 13), 1962-1965, undated; (6 folders) (Box 9)
    - Chicago factories for Serpico murals, [late 1960s] (Box 9)
    - Views of countryside and ocean, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Small town scenes, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Urban scenes (see also sol 13), undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Industrial scenes, undated (Box 9)
    - Old houses, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous buildings, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Horses and cattle, undated; (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Skeletons of a human and a horse, undated (Box 9)
    - The circus, undated (Box 9)
    - The moon, undated (Box 9)
  - Events, Lindbergh kidnapping trial, 1935 (Box 9)
  - Events, presentation of bust of Norman Thomas, [circa 1965] (Box 9)
  - Events, presentation of the bust of Eleanor Roosevelt, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Events, exhibition installations and gallery openings (see also sol 13), 1949-1972; (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Travel, Italy, 1964, undated; (6 folders) (Box 10)
  - Travel, New York City (including views of the 1939 World's Fair), [1930]-1939; (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Travel, of Kashmir/India by Hartmann, undated; (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Travel, miscellaneous travel, undated (Box 10)
  - Artwork, album, undated (Box 13 (sol))
  - Artwork, miscellaneous drawings, undated; (16 folders; 10 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1 and MGP 4) (Box 10)
  - Artwork, paintings, 1953-1977; (21 folders; 1 glass plate negative housed in MGP 4) (Box 10)
  - Artwork, for murals, undated; (3 folders; 3 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 4) (Box 11)
  - Artwork, sculpture, [1939]-1986; (42 folders) (Box 11)
  - Artwork, by others, undated (Box 11)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, 11 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, 6 Glass negatives (Box MGP 4)
  - Transparencies of Lazzari, 1958-1978; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of family and friends, 1958-1972; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of Lazzari's studio, 1958-1978; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies, of gallery installations, 1958-1970; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of works on paper by Lazzari, 1963-1971; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of paintings, 1955-1978, undated; (4 slide boxes) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of sculpture, 1955-1978; (7 slide boxes) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of travel locations, 1958-1972; (1 slide box) (Box 12)
  - Transparencies of nudes (5 stereo slides), undated (Box 12)
- Motion Picture Film, undated; Series 9; (box 12; 1 folder)
  This series consists of an undated 16mm safety motion picture film "U.S. Soldiers on the March from Europe to Pacific".
- Artifact, undated; Series 10; (box 12; 1 folder)
  This series comprises a book of artwork constructed from thin wood slats loosely bound one on top of the other with twine, displaying rows of characters from an unidentified language written or printed onto both sides of each slat.